Frederick K. Articuno

Phone - (804) 704-0334 | Email - mckiyoshi@gmail.com | Location - Colonial Heights, VA 23834 | Github - github.com/fkarticuno | LinkedIn - linkedin.com/in/frederick-articuno | Portfolio - fkarticuno.github.io/CodingPortfolio

Summary

Full-Stack *MERN* Web Developer leveraging experience in numerous frameworks and languages. Known as a curious mind with a continuous focus on the next steps and perpetual improvement. With each project, the goal is to use current knowledge to develop a stable platform from which to expand from the minimum viable product into the frontiers of technology. Excited to leverage skills in the future as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team in order to build better experiences on the web and develop more concise code for the future.

Technical Skills

MongoDB | Express | React | Node | CSS | HTML | Firebase | Git | CSS | Bootstrap | JavaScript | JQuery | Timers | Ajax | MySQL | Handlebars | Sequelize | API Integration | Heroku | User Auth | Java | CMS

Projects

Coding Portfolio / https://github.com/fkarticuno/CodingPortfolio
Portfolio displaying progress and achievements developing basic, intermediate and advanced apps using various languages, packages, frameworks, engines and database models. All culminating into a demo friendly environment to showcase the expertise gained through countless hours of development and refactoring.

Uses: HTML CSS Bootstrap JavaScript JQuery GitHub-Pages

Moneta / https://mc-moneta.herokuapp.com / https://github.com/vin-cent321/Moneta

Moneta is a full stack *MERN* platform for patients at any stage of Alzheimer's/Dementia to keep their mind and brain stimulated. Brain teasers/memory/image and word association games have been scientifically proven to be useful throughout the lives of people afflicted with the disease.

Uses: MongoDB Express.js React.js Node.js Axios Passport Moment OpenWeather-API

Drinking Well / https://github.com/jckent/actual_malware
This *MERN* app allows users to learn about mixology, and try new things by giving them recipes for random or user selected beveragesLeveraging express and node.js to provide server and routing, mysql for databasing, passport.js for authentication while making calls to a robust beverage API to return drink names, images, ingredients, measurements, and instructions along with a second API call to YouTube to provide an instructional video.

Uses: Bootstrap HTML CSS JQuery JavaScript MySQL Heroku Express Sequelize

Eat-Da-Burger / https://eat-da-burger-fka.herokuapp.com / https://github.com/fkarticuno/burger

A restaurant style app that lets users input the names of burgers they would like to eat, when submitted the app will store the burger in its database, compile a JSON variant, and reproduce the updated list of burgers. While in the 'waiting area' burgers have buttons to trigger CSS changes on favorite and to devour the selected burger.

Uses: CSS Bootstrap HTML JavaScript MySQL Sequelize JQuery

Work Experience

Capital One; Chester, Virginia

08/2015 - 05/2019

Sr. Risk coordinator (02/2017 – 05/2019)

Managed inbound and outbound collection calls while performing account level research, updating account information, and completing appropriate documentation to ensure accurate reporting.

- Became a Google Guide to assist in transitioning from Microsoft Office Suite to Google Suite.
- Created Cure Estimator app to project cost analysis for customers, Awarded Spot Award.

Risk coordinator (02/2016 – 02/2017)

Maintained compliance by adhering to all Federal, State and Capital One Regulations while balancing business intent and our customer's needs to design creative solutions that make our customers lives better and show advocacy to our customers.

- Received 4 ROAR awards for performing as top 1%.
- Overcame objections that customers have about making payments toward their account(s) and help them to understand their account(s) and responsibilities.

Sr. Risk representative (08/2015 – 02/2016)

Help customers build and retain strong credit standing.

- Boosted customer engagement by helping clients build and retain a strong credit standing.
- Helped Capital One maintain our customers for life by providing exceptional call quality on every call, building on Capital One's brand through great customer service.

AmeriCorps; Petersburg, Virginia

08/2012 - 05/2013

Volunteer

Provided Plumbing services to include installation and maintenance on fountains, sinks, showers, tubs, gas and electric heating / cooling, potable water source routing, gray water/sewer water drainage along with landscaping, technological up training, roofing, painting, and bioswale installation.

• Obtained CPR, First Aid, AED, ServeSafe, LEED, OSHA and Forklift Operations certifications.

United States Marine Corps; Virginia Beach, Virginia

08/2009 - 8/2017

Data Link Coordinator - E5 Sergeant

Completed MAJIC (Multi-tactical-data-link Advanced Joint Interoperability Course)

System Configuration Coordinator - E4 Corporal

Sourced and maintained interoperability equipment. Awarded Promotion to E5.

Tactical Air Traffic Controller - E4 Corporal

• Managed Air traffic in/out of designated AORs. Completed operations training.

Assistant Controller - E3 - Lance Corporal

• Completed JTIDS (Joint Tactical Information Distribution Systems). Awarded Promotion to E4.

Surveillance Operator - E2 PFC

• Acquired Secret Clearance. Awarded promotion to E3.

Education

Full Stack Coding Certification - University Of Richmond

Capital One Tech College - John Tyler Community College

Marine Corps Air Ground Combat Center - Tidewater Community College